<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Шифроград</string>
    <string name="tab_cipher">Шифр</string>
    <string name="navigation_bottom">Полоса навигации</string>
    <string name="first_launch_greeting_text">Это игра про декодирование шифра замены. Одной букве английского языка соответствует один символ. Выберите уровень во вкладке МЕНЮ (иконка трех линий). Находите знакомые слова в зашифрованном тексте во вкладке ШИФР (иконка домика) и указывайте пары СИМВОЛ-БУКВА во вкладке ИЗМЕНИТЬ (иконка карандаша). Привязывание помечается цветом в зависимости от правильности (красный-зеленый). Чтобы удалить привязывание, нажмите на надпись о нем (\"X >>> A\"). Удачи!</string>
    <string name="tab_edit">Изменить</string>
    <string name="map_symbol">Привязать символ:</string>
    <string name="to_letter">К букве:</string>
    <string name="map">Привязать!</string>
    <string name="cipher_text" translatable="false">INTRODUCING MYSELF.
hi! nice to meet you! my name is john smith. i am 19 and a student in college. the best food for me is bisque - a thick cream soup. i go to college in new york. my favorite courses are geometry, french, and history. english is my hardest course because i am quite lazy to prepare to exams. my professors are very friendly and smart. it’s my second year in college now. i love it! i live in a big house on ivy street. it’s near the college campus. i share the house with three other students. their names are bill, tony, and paul. we help each other with homework. on the weekend, we play football together. i have a younger brother. he just started high school. he is 14 and lives with my parents. they live on mulberry street in boston. sometimes they visit me in new york. i am happy when they visit. my mom always brings me sweets and candy when they come. i really miss them, too!$$MEMORY.
in 1885, hermann ebbinghaus studied his own memory. he wanted to know how quickly he forgot new information. he gave himself tests after different periods of time to see how much he forgot each time. the result is called the forgetting curve. we forget the fastest in the first 24 hours. and then we forget more and more but the speed slows down over time. after about six days, we have forgotten most of the new information. if we revise the information we make the memory stronger and we slow down the speed of forgetting. if we revise again and again, we can leave longer and longer periods of time between revisions. time is not the only thing that makes us forget something. if we are tired or under stress, we forget faster. if the information was difficult to understand we will forget it faster too. but things that are very important or meaningful to us are easier to remember.$$FAIRIES.
while most people no longer believe in fairies, only a hundred years ago some people were very willing to think they might exist. in 1917, 16-year-old elsie wright took two photos of her cousin, nine-year-old frances griffiths, sitting with fairies. some photography experts thought they were fake, while others weren’t sure. but arthur conan doyle, the writer of the sherlock holmes detective stories, believed they were real. he published the original pictures, and three more the girls took for him, in a magazine called the strand, in 1920. the girls only admitted the photos were fake years later in 1983, created using pictures of dancers that elsie copied from a book. we owe many of our modern ideas about fairies to shakespeare and stories from the 18th and 19th centuries. although we can see the origins of fairies as far back as the ancient greeks, we can see similar creatures in many cultures. the earliest fairy-like creatures can be found in the greek idea that trees and rivers had spirits called dryads and nymphs. some people think these creatures were originally the gods of earlier, pagan religions that worshipped nature. they were replaced by the greek and roman gods, and then later by the christian god, and became smaller, less powerful figures as they lost importance.$$RAINBOWS.
in ireland, it rains a lot and there isn’t much sun. but sometimes, when the sun comes out after the rain, you can see pretty colours in the sky–that’s a rainbow. old stories from ireland say that a leprechaun, a small magical man, hides his pot full of gold at the end of the rainbow. you must follow the rainbow to find the gold, but it’s very hard. rainbows always move when you get near, and no one can find the gold. in irish culture, if you see a rainbow, good things will happen. hawaii is called the rainbow capital of the world. after light rain, often the sun comes out, and you can see the rainbow. in native hawaiian culture, rainbows are signs that people receive from the gods. some people believe that rainbows help the spirits of dead people travel from the human world to another world. in hawaii, a rainbow reminds people they are not alone because someone always looks after them. in some african cultures, a rainbow may be a spirit that looks like a snake, bringing good or bad luck, depending on how it feels. for this reason, many people think that a rainbow is a message that something big–good or bad–is going to happen soon. in aboriginal australian stories, there’s a powerful snake called the rainbow serpent that lives in water, and it’s very old. the rainbow serpent made rivers, mountains, and lakes when planet earth was born. if people respect the land, the snake will be good to them. if they don’t, it may bring storms or floods. for aboriginal people, the rainbow helps us remember that we must respect nature. in the north of europe, old stories say that the rainbow is a bridge. it’s the bridge between our world and asgard, the home of the gods like odin and thor. only gods and brave people can walk across it. the guardian at the beginning of the bridge stops bad people from entering asgard.$$COLLECTIONS.
petra engels owns 19,571 erasers, carol vaughn has 1,221 bars of soap, and ralf shroder has a collection of 14,502 packets of sugar. many people love to collect things, but why? psychologists and collectors have different opinions. the psychologist carl jung believed that collecting is part of our ancient human history. thousands of years ago, humans collected nuts and berries. they kept them carefully and ate them when there was no food. the best collectors survived long cold winters or seasons without rain. their genes passed to future generations. nowadays, we still have a collecting instinct. art collector, werner muensterberger, thinks that collecting is linked to childhood. he believes we collect in order to feel safe and secure. while babies hold blankets or toys to feel safe when their mother isn’t there, adults collect things to stop feeling lonely or anxious. autograph collector mark baker agrees that collecting is emotional, but he doesn’t collect to reduce anxiety. “for me, it’s the excitement,” he says. “i love trying to get a famous person’s autograph. sometimes i succeed, and sometimes i fail. also, by collecting autographs, i feel connected to famous people. i don’t just watch them on television. i actually meet them.” these are just a few reasons for collecting. do you know any people with collections? why do they collect?
    </string>
    <string name="tab_level_select">Уровни</string>
    <string name="level_sign">"УРОВЕНЬ "</string>
    <string name="delete_progress">Удалить прогресс в уровне</string>
    <string name="are_you_sure">Вы уверены?</string>
    <string name="toast_copied">Скопировано!</string>
    <string name="top_bar_menu">Меню</string>
    <string name="top_bar_export">Экспортировать прогресс в буфер обмена</string>
    <string name="top_bar_import">Импортировать прогресс из буфера обмена</string>
    <string name="toast_error">Произошла ошибка!</string>
    <string name="toast_success">Успешно!</string>
</resources>